<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rambling on Writing</title>
    <link>https://mayukhdeb.github.io/writing/categories/rambling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rambling on Writing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mayukhdeb.github.io/writing/categories/rambling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Train Journeys</title>
      <link>https://mayukhdeb.github.io/writing/post/on-train-hourneys/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mayukhdeb.github.io/writing/post/on-train-hourneys/</guid>
      <description>A perfectly known future is already the past When you’re on a long train journey through India, you’ll see a lot of “small stations” where most of the trains dont stop. Even if they do, that’s usually not for the sake of someone to get off/board the train. The trains stop there only when they’re ahead of time, or if they have some issue with the route ahead.
When I look at these stations, I feel a weird urge to get off into that small station, especially during night time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Pigeons don&#39;t fly off to Hawaii</title>
      <link>https://mayukhdeb.github.io/writing/post/why-pigeons-dont-fly-to-hawaii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mayukhdeb.github.io/writing/post/why-pigeons-dont-fly-to-hawaii/</guid>
      <description>I live in a place where we have a lot of pigeons, most of them live in the abandoned/unused flats in some of the buildings. Nobody likes them, but still you&amp;rsquo;ll see little bowls of grains and water on a large number of the windows. We don&amp;rsquo;t like them, but we feed them anyways.
I personally keep a bowl of water too. When they see that the bowl&amp;rsquo;s empty, they just stare into it and then fly away after a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purulia</title>
      <link>https://mayukhdeb.github.io/writing/post/purulia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mayukhdeb.github.io/writing/post/purulia/</guid>
      <description>Not far from the city of Kolkata lies a small district where you&amp;rsquo;ll still find people living lives long forgotten by the city dwellers. It&amp;rsquo;s a place which still prefers to watch the world zoom ahead through one of it&amp;rsquo;s national highways. This post is a small and rather forgettable (unless you&amp;rsquo;re the author himself) memoir of some of my overly specific memories in Purulia.
Of course like any other road-trip I&amp;rsquo;ve taken with my brother and my dad, this one also started with us stopping by in the morning for chaa/chai (bengali/hindi for &amp;ldquo;tea&amp;rdquo;) on a small shop near Shaktigarh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School</title>
      <link>https://mayukhdeb.github.io/writing/post/school/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mayukhdeb.github.io/writing/post/school/</guid>
      <description>One of my older posts describes a little bit about my experiences in school. But at this point I feel like it deserves a place of it&amp;rsquo;s own. Which is here.
The school in which I spent a large part of my childhood was Amrita Vidyalayam Kolkata. It was the first time that I had the chance to ride on a school bus. The problem with the bus was that it&amp;rsquo;s pickup point was a little far from home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI is only as powerful as the language it understands</title>
      <link>https://mayukhdeb.github.io/writing/post/ai-is-only-as-powerful-as-the-language-it-understands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mayukhdeb.github.io/writing/post/ai-is-only-as-powerful-as-the-language-it-understands/</guid>
      <description>You cannot evolve faster than your language because the language defines the culture of meaning ~ Terrence McKenna
There are theories out there which state that the world out there is completely different from the one we perceive. Much like a &amp;ldquo;dream world&amp;rdquo; which correlates with the real world as mentioned by Joshua Bach in one of his appearances in the Lex Fridman Podcast. We can look at our perception as a compression algorithm which gives us just enough information about the world to do the things we do.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>